# OMAR WARSAME

#### DEVOPS ENGINEER

#### CONTACT

+44 75 7275 8030

 $\bowtie$ 

jubawarsame@gmail.com



https://devsom.co.uk



https://www.linkedin.com/in/owarsame



https://github.com/OmarWarsame



London, UK

#### PROFILE

Currently an AWS Professional with over 4 years of experience in IT industry comprising of User/Systems Administration, and Software Configuration Management. Experienced in automation, configuring and deploying infrastructure on AWS, also familiar with various CI/CD tools, looking forward into transitioning to the next challenge of DevOps engineering. I have experience in client-facing positions, have achieved 1 AWS certification and did other multiple tech-related courses including a DevOps bootcamp whilst working full-time

#### SKILLS

- Amazon AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda, etc.)
- IaC tools (**Terraform**, CloudFormation, etc.)
- Linux and Windows system administration
- Version control systems (Git & GitLab)
- Configuration management (Ansible)
- Orchestration (Kubernetes)
- CI/CD (Jenkins)
- Containerisation (Docker)
- Agile methodologies (Scrum)
- Monitoring and alerting (Prometheus, Grafana)
- Shell Scripting
- · Networking and security concepts
- · Collaboration and communication skills
- Decision making
- · Troubleshooting and problem-solving skills

# COURSES

- DevOps for Beginners
- AWS Solution Architect (Certified)
- · CompTia A+, Network+, and Linux+
- · CCNA Router and Switch
- HTML CSS and JavaScript

## EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science Mogadishu University Aug 1999 - Jun 2003 Mogadishu, Somalia

# CORE COMPETENCIES

- Expertise in cloud for building scalable, reliable, and cost-effective infrastructure.
- Adept at utilising **Git** for branching, merging, and collaboration within **dev** teams.
- Implementation of recovery plans, resulting in a seamless recovery.
- Strong skill to maintain clear, concise, and up-to-date **technical documentation**.
- Reduced AWS infrastructure **costs** by **25**% using strategic resource provisioning.
- Proficient in implementing and supporting AWS based instances and services.
- Experience in security hardening with IAM roles and policies.
- Experience in troubleshooting and resolving technical issues in AWS.
- Ability to continuously learn and work independently with minimal supervision.

#### WORK HISTORY

#### Solutions Architect

Luul Solutions Ltd

London

09/2021 - till date

- Proficiently use AWS services: EKS, IAM, EC2, and CloudFront.
- Manage source code with Git, and GitLab. Resolved merge conflicts.
- Create shell scripts for daily tasks: backups, and environment setup.
- Implemented AWS security measures, for least privilege access.
- Infrastructure deployment on AWS by employing EC2, RDS, CloudFront, VPC, CloudWatch etc.
- Configured CloudWatch alarm rules for operational and performance metrics for our AWS resources and applications.
- Configured CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins connected to GitHub and built Stage environments.
- Integrated Ansible control with nodes and deployed playbooks to automation configuration of servers.
- Designed, secured and cost optimised highly available and fault tolerant infrastructure in AWS.
- Successfully deployed and configured infrastructure using Ansible.
- Review and identify AWS accounts with excessive permissions.
- Knowledge of **network** protocols, **routing** and managing LAN/WAN.
- Understanding of Internet **protocols** (TCP/IP, DNS, HTTP, **SSL**).
- Automate configurations with Ansible, reducing manual effort by 60 hours/week.
  Collaborated with developers in the SDLC using agile methodologies.
- Designed, built, and configured Ubuntu Linux servers and VM's.
- Built and maintained automated CI/CD processes for applications with Jenkins, eliminating up to 70% of manual work which drastically reduced human error.
- Leverage automated DevOps tools deployment and blue-green deployment patterns and strategies.

## Deskside Support Engineer

BlackRock

London

11/2020 - 09/2021

- · Monitoring systems for optimal operation.
- Incidents and request logs, prioritising on ServiceNow.
- Support trading applications for deployment, troubleshooting.
- Support remote users and build replacement devices if necessary.
- Provide technical support on services specified in the Services Catalogue.
- Support users working from home and build replacement devices if necessary.
- Reset passwords, unlock or disable accounts on Active Directory.

# Help Desk Support Specialist

Globalnet ICT

London

08/2019 - 11/2020

- Unlocking, resetting and disabling accounts on Active Directory.
- Installing and troubleshooting Windows operating systems.
- Adding network printers through print management.